export const JEWELLERYA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Identify the correct procedure for appreciating a jewellery item from the options.",
A: "Description, identification, technical qualities, and interpretation",
B: "Identification, description, technical qualities, and interpretation",
C: "Interpretation, technical qualities, identification, and description",
D: "Technical qualities, description, interpretation, and identification",
answer: "B. Identification, description, technical qualities, and interpretation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. One of the key factors in preparing a business plan for a proposed industry is to",
A: "explain the concept of management.",
B: "look for more labour.",
C: "identify a need to satisfy.",
D: "solicit for financial assistance.",
answer: "C. identify a need to satisfy.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The main purpose for organizing a jewellery exhibition is to",
A: "advertize the venue.",
B: "build a portfolio.",
C: "establish an industry.",
D: "promote sales.",
answer: "D. promote sales.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Fastening devices in jewellery are normally classified as",
A: "claps.",
B: "clips.",
C: "findings.",
D: "hinges.",
answer: "C. findings.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A major disadvantage of vitreous enamel is the tendency to",
A: "absorb moisture from the environment.",
B: "be affected by fungus.",
C: "crack when the support is stressed.",
D: "melt if exposed to sunlight.",
answer: "C. crack when the support is stressed.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following statements best describes scorching?",
A: "A thin glass-like coating, fused on the surface of clay",
B: "Cutting linear patterns on the surface of objects",
C: "Decorating items by burning with a hot metal",
D: "Using punch and hammer to indent a surface",
answer: "C. Decorating items by burning with a hot metal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. In wet charging, enamel powder is combined with",
A: "agua.",
B: "frit.",
C: "gum tragacanth.",
D: "metallic oxide.",
answer: "C. gum tragacanth.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Choose the appropriate technique for decorating paper beads from the options.",
A: "Enamelling",
B: "Etching",
C: "Patination",
D: "Stippling",
answer: "D. Stippling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The best condition for storing jewellery is to keep them in a",
A: "damp and airtight box.",
B: "dry and airy box.",
C: "greasy and moist box.",
D: "humid and warm box.",
answer: "B. dry and airy box.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The technique used in polishing large quantities of jewellery items is",
A: "buffing.",
B: "draw filing.",
C: "pickling.",
D: "sandblasting.",
answer: "A. buffing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Choose the appropriate method for preparing pickling solution.",
A: "Acid must be poured gradually into water",
B: "Acid must be more than water",
C: "Water must be poured quickly into acid",
D: "Water must be more than acid",
answer: "A. Acid must be poured gradually into water",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Select the finishing technique in jewellery from the options.",
A: "Casting",
B: "Pairing",
C: "Patination",
D: "Repousse",
answer: "C. Patination",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Identify an abrasive compound from the options below.",
A: "Beeswax",
B: "Paint",
C: "Shellac",
D: "Tripoli",
answer: "D. Tripoli",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Before inserting a piercing saw blade into a metal, the metal must be",
A: "annealed.",
B: "drilled.",
C: "heated.",
D: "polished.",
answer: "B. drilled.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The bodkin can only be used on",
A: "gold.",
B: "ivory.",
C: "pebble.",
D: "silver",
answer: "B. ivory.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following chemicals is best for removing pen marks after engraving?",
A: "Acetone",
B: "Methanol alcohol",
C: "Methylated spirit",
D: "Varnish",
answer: "A. Acetone",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The most suitable tool for slicing leather is",
A: "chisel.",
B: "hacksaw.",
C: "skive.",
D: "spatula.",
answer: "C. skive.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Sterling silver is an alloy of",
A: "aluminium and fine silver.",
B: "bronze and fine silver.",
C: "fine silver and copper.",
D: "fine silver and zinc.",
answer: "C. fine silver and copper.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following metals has the lowest melting point?",
A: "Brass",
B: "Copper",
C: "Gold",
D: "Silver",
answer: "A. Brass",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following factors determines the price of a jewellery item?",
A: "Durability of the material used",
B: "Good human relations",
C: "Production cost and profit margin",
D: "Variable cost and fixed cost",
answer: "C. Production cost and profit margin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Select the pair of vocations in jewellery from the following options.",
A: "Engraving and gilding",
B: "Forging and gilding",
C: "Lapidary and engraving",
D: "Welding and soldering",
answer: "C. Lapidary and engraving",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The final production of a jewellerâ€™s work can be derived from the",
A: "idea development.",
B: "pre-imaging.",
C: "prototype.",
D: "working-drawing.",
answer: "C. prototype.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Joints to be soldered are covered with loam to prevent",
A: "glowing.",
B: "hardening.",
C: "melting.",
D: "oxidizing.",
answer: "D. oxidizing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following artists has contributed to the development of jewellery in Ghana?",
A: "Ablade Glover",
B: "Ampim Tetteh",
C: "Mama Pee",
D: "Charlotte Hagan",
answer: "A. Ablade Glover",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. In the Ghanaian society, female beauty may be symbolized by the use of",
A: "circles.",
B: "ovals.",
C: "squares.",
D: "triangles.",
answer: "A. circles.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Wedding rings bought by couples in shops are usually presented in",
A: "primary state.",
B: "satchets.",
C: "secondary state.",
D: "wrappers.",
answer: "C. secondary state.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In which industry is recycling an important production technique. In the making of",
A: "clay beads.",
B: "glass beads.",
C: "plastic beads.",
D: "seed beads.",
answer: "C. plastic beads.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A major feature which makes bamboo suitable for beadmaking is its",
A: "durability.",
B: "flexibility.",
C: "natural holes.",
D: "permanent colours.",
answer: "B. flexibility.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following metals are classified as noble?",
A: "Brass, gold, and copper",
B: "Copper, iron, and lead",
C: "Lead, platinum, and tin",
D: "Platinum, gold, and copper",
answer: "D. Platinum, gold, and copper",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Bone, cane, and wood beads are decorated by",
A: "buffing.",
B: "firing.",
C: "heating.",
D: "scorching.",
answer: "D. scorching.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following metals is prone to the formation of verdigris?",
A: "Bronze",
B: "Copper",
C: "Gold",
D: "Silver",
answer: "B. Copper",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. When producing ear screws, the problem of thick wire is resolved by",
A: "drawing.",
B: "milling.",
C: "pulling.",
D: "rolling.",
answer: "A. drawing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Choose the inorganic material from the options below.",
A: "Bamboo",
B: "Bone",
C: "Clay y",
D: "Rubber",
answer: "C. Clay",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following tools facilitates combustion?",
A: "Bellows",
B: "Bodkin",
C: "Pair of tongs",
D: "Soldering iron",
answer: "A. Bellows",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following explains principles of design?",
A: "A combination of lines and dots.",
B: "Creation of unit repeat patterns.",
C: "The arrangement of similar elements.",
D: "The order of arranging elements.",
answer: "D. The order of arranging elements.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following tools is best for forming rings?",
A: "File",
B: "Mandrel",
C: "Pliers",
D: "Tweezers",
answer: "B. Mandrel",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Artists often make preliminary designs in order to",
A: "avoid wastage.",
B: "become popular.",
C: "get more money.",
D: "increase production.",
answer: "A. avoid wastage.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The top arc of the traditional stool in Ghana, symbolizes",
A: "Godâ€™s justice and fairness.",
B: "greatness of the man in a society.",
C: "support of the earth.",
D: "the loving embrace of a mother.",
answer: "D. the loving embrace of a mother.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The ancient Ashanti gold weights were used for",
A: "charming.",
B: "identifying.",
C: "measuring.",
D: "worshipping.",
answer: "C. measuring.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following gives colour to enamel?",
A: "Borax",
B: "Glaze oxides",
C: "Metallic oxides",
D: "Resin",
answer: "C. Metallic oxides",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]